EMILY OWAKI

JAVASCRIPT DEVELOPER

SUMMARY

I'm a software engineer with experience working on legacy projects and using that knowledge to avoid pitfalls when building from the ground up. My background is working with Javascript, React/Redux, Backbone and occasionally Ruby. I'm comfortable interacting and planning with product owners and enjoy mentoring and onboarding junior developers.

CONTACT

■ emily.owaki@gmail.com

**** 203-241-6303

in emilyowaki

jabbowaki

SKILLS

Javascript/ES6 React/Redux Immutable Git Ruby on Rails JQuery

Pair Programming Agile Jira

EMPLOYMENT

Jellyvision · Chicago, IL Software Engineer Aug 2016 to Current

- Focused on building internal and external facing applications with the ALEX Benefits Counselor ecosystem
- Contributed to Talentshow, an internal tool written in React/Redux that allows users to create "conversations" that are media rich interactive content
- Created a runtime engine (React/Redux) that takes output from Talentshow and creates responsive HTML5 conversations with audio and animations
- Developed front end framework for handling activity handling and dependency management using Backbone.js
- Mentored junior developers on team codebases, design patterns, agile methodologies, and best practices

Feb 2015 to Aug 2016

Jr Software Engineer

- Created first version of responsive HTML5 ALEX Benefits Counselor using Backbone
- Used Backbone and VideoJS to create a customizable SPA to explain 1095 forms
- Built complex email templates with conditional logic and tested in Litmus
- Contributed to open source Ruby gem for CSS inlining in ERB templates

Dev Bootcamp

Apr 2016 to Aug 2016

Phase 0 Teaching Assistant

- Taught pair programming, Git, Ruby and Javascript fundamentals
- Guided incoming Dev Bootcamp students through remote pair programming sessions
- Reviewed and graded student assignments for competency

VOLUNTEERING

Railsbridge · Teaching Assistant

2015 to Current

- Led students through workshop curriculum covering Git, Ruby, and Rails
- Assisted in setting up development environments for incoming students
- Debugged student code and taught introduction to fundamentals

Girl Develop It · Teaching Assistant

2014 to Current

• Assisted with the following courses: Javascript 101, Intro to jQuery, Intro Git/Github and Beginner HTML/CSS

EDUCATION

Dev Bootcamp

Columbia College Chicago BA Music Management 2008